Register of the Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers, 1899-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1966
  - Djilas, Milovan. "Djilas Learns about Communism" by B. Soumar, n.d. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Donovan, William J., speech on Soviet-American relations, 1947 December 4 (Folder 16)
  - Drohojowski, Jan
    - Case of, 1941-1942 (Folder 17)
    - Moscow Conference, 1945 June. Memoirs, clipping, 1959 (Folder 18)
  - Escapes - Poland
    - General. List for 1951 (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Hajdukiewicz, Jan, 1953 (Folder 2)
    - Jarecki, Franciszek, 1953 (Folder 3)
    - Klimowicz, Antoni, 1954. Clippings (Folder 4)
    - Korowicz, Marek, 1953-1954
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Clippings (Folder 6)
  - Fischer, Ernst - Soviet plans toward Germany, 1944 (Folder 7)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations
    - 1945 - Quebec City (Folder 8)
    - 1946 - Copenhagen
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Poland's need for assistance (Folder 10)
  - Geneva Conference, 1955 (Folder 11)
  - Gomulka, Wladyslaw. Clippings, 1961-1962 (Folder 12)
  - Grabski, Stanislaw - Analysis of Poland's political situation in late 1944. Typescript, 1944 (Folder 13)
  - Gryziewicz, Stanislaw, "Glowne problemy rozwoju gospodarczego Polski w okresie 1919-1939," 1951. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Harriman, William Averell. Memorandum on possibilty of war, 1952 (Folder 15)
  - Hauke, Hugon. Clippings, 1955 (Folder 16)
  - Hauke-Nowak, Aleksander - Rzad Obrony Narodowej, 1943 (Folder 17)
  - Hendrikcs, Jozef. Manuscript on evaluation of pre-war aiforce, plan of reform, 1939 (Folder 18)
  - International Rescue Committee, 1947-1951 (Folder 19)
  - Iranek, Osmecki, K., Opinion from Home Army circles of, 1943 (Folder 20)
  - Jews
    - American Jewish Committee, 1943 (Folder 21)
    - Occupied Poland
      - General
        - Clippings
          - General, 1918, 1941-1942, 1962-1963 (Folder 22)
          - Dziennik Polski, London, 1942 November (Folder 23)
          - Polish Jewish Observer, London, 1942 December-1943 January (Folder 24)
        - Reports
          - 1939 (Folder 25)
          - 1942 (Folder 26)
      - Polska Partia Socjalistyczna - Bund declaration on post-war Poland, 1941 (Folder 27)
      - Reprezentacja Zydostwa Polskiego - Tel Aviv. Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1942 December (Folder 28)
      - Warsaw Ghetto
        - Christians in, n.d. (Folder 29)
        - Litman, Chaskel, reports from Sweden, 1943 (Folder 30)
      - Zygielbojm, Szmul, 1942-1944 (Folder 31)
    - Palestine - Religious and political groups, 1943? (Folder 32)
    - Post-war
      - Communist pogroms. Report, 1947 (in English) (Folder 33)
      - Kielce, 1946 (Folder 34)
      - Situation of Jews in late 1940s (Folder 35)
    - Pro-Communist elements, 1944 (Folder 36)
  - Kamienski, Jan - Embezzlement of funds, 1953 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Karski, Jan, review of Samuel Sharp, White Eagle on the Red Field, 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1943
    - General
      - Clippings
        - 1943-1951 (Folder 3)
        - 1952 (Folder 4)
        - 1953-1963 (Folder 5)
      - Excerpts from literature, 1946-1951 (Folder 6)
      - List of victims, partial, ca. 500 (Folder 7)
      - Printed matter
        - 1944 (Folder 8)
        - 1951-1952 (Folder 9)
      - Reports
        - "Katin, the Mass Murder of Polish Prisoners of War: Report Prepared by the Association of Former Soviet Political Prisoners and Presented by the Polish Socialist Party to the International Socialist Conference, Copenhagen, 1-3 June, 1950." Mimeograph, 1950 (Folder 10)
        - Masowe morderstwo polskich jencow wojennych w Katyniu
          - English edition, The Mass Murder of Polish Prisoners of War in Katyn, 1946 (Folder 11)
          - Polish edition, n.d. (Folder 12)
        - "Supplementary Reports on Facts and Documents Concerning the Katyn Massacre." Mimeograph, 1947 (Folder 13)
      - Testimonies of former prisoners - Bronislaw Mlynarski - Solikamsk camp, 1941 (Folder 14)
    - American Committee for the Investigation of the Katyn Massacre
      - Clippings, 1952 (Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 16)
      - Reports
        - "Ideological Special," 1952 (Folder 17)
        - Interim, 1952 (Folder 18)
      - Statements and testimonies
        - General (Folder 19)
        - Anders, Wladyslaw and Mlynarski, Bronislaw (Folder 20)
        - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw, 1952 (Folder 21)
    - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw
      - Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Folder 22)
      - Personal notes (Folder 23)
      - Speeches and interviews (Folder 24)
  - Kennedy, Edward - Trip to Poland, 1922. Polish press clippings (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald
    - Interview for Izvestia, 1961 November (Folder 2)
    - Obituaries, 1963 (Folder 3)
    - Speech, United States Senate, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Khrushchev, Nikita, speech, XXth Congress of Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1956 February 24. Printed copy (Polish translation) (Folder 5)
  - Klibanski, Ignacy - Liquidation of Polish communist party, 1955 (Folder 6)
  - Kot, Stanislaw
    - General
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Clippings (Folder 8)
      - Writings
        - "Linia polityczna PSL," 1950 (Folder 9)
        - "Listy z Rosji do Generala Sikorskiego," 1956? Typescript (Folder 10)
    - Biography and bibliography (Folder 11)
    - Mieszkowski, Jozef, Case of (after his return to Poland), 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Lane, Arthur B., 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Lange, Oskar, speech, National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1943 December 20. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Lieberman, Herman (Folder 15)
  - Lipski, Jozef, "Kilka uwag o dzialalnosci ambasadora Jozefa Lipskiego w okresie od czasu do czerwca do marca 1939 roku," n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - Lithuanians in Germany, 1954 (Folder 17)
  - London International Assembly. Minutes of meetings and reports, 1941-1943
    - Index (Folder 18)
    - Nos. 1-71 (Folder 19)
    - Nos. 72-138 (Folder 20)
    - Nos. 139-213 (Folder 21)
    - Nos. 214-259 (Folder 22)
  - Lovestone, Jay, Communist and Workers Parties Manifesto Adopted November-December 1960: Interpretation and Analysis, 1961 (Folder 23)
  - Mackiewicz-Cat, Stanislaw
    - 1943 (Folder 24)
    - 1958 (Folder 25)
  - Malewicz-Hancza, R., 1945 (Folder 26)
  - Mantel, Felix, 1963 (Folder 27)
  - Miksche, F. O., "Notes on the Political Conduct of the Cold War," 1953. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - Modelski, Izydor
    - General
      - Letter to the President of Poland, Wladyslaw Raczkiewicz, 1943 (Folder 29)
      - Obituaries, 1962 (Folder 30)
      - Writing, "Ku realizacji mysli o Wielkiej Polsce," 1940. Typescript (Folder 31)
    - Battle of 1920 (Folder 32)
    - Resignation from diplomatic post, 1948 (Folder 33)
  - Naczelne Sily Zbrojne. Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe. Circular, 1946 (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Narodno Trudovoi Soyuz Rossiiskikh Solidaristov. Program, 1958 (Folder 2)
  - Nichol, David, report on trip to Russia, 1944 (Folder 3)
  - Oberlander, Theodor, 1963 (Folder 4)
  - Oder-Neisse Area
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Paris Conference, 1949
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Clippings (Folder 7)
    - United States. Congress, 1957 (Folder 8)
  - Osrodek Badan Socjologicznych. Report, 1947-1948 (Folder 9)
  - Paderewski, Ignacy - Unveiling of commemorative monument in Morges, Switzerland, 1948 July 3 (Folder 10)
  - Paprocki, Stanislaw, "Struktura narodowosciowa ZSRR," 1949. Mimeograph (Folder 11)
  - Partito Comunista Italiano - Resolution on situation in Yugoslavia, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - Pax, Structure of. Clipping, 1957 (Folder 13)
  - Petkov, Nicola, memorial speech, 1953. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Poland
    - Amnesty, 1956 (Folder 15)
    - Communist policy toward farmers, 1959? (Folder 16)
    - Custom tariffs, 1957-1960 (Folder 17)
    - Elections
      - General
        - Essay by Milan Hodza on free elections in Eastern Europe, 1943 (Folder 18)
        - Pre-1939 statistics (Folder 19)
      - 1947
        - Electoral law (Folder 20)
        - Falsifications. "Dokumenty falszerstw wyborczych." Typescript
          - Part 1, 1946 December 18
            - General
              - Copies (Folder 21)
              - Final report
                - Polish (Folder 22)
                - English (Folder 23)
            - Enclosures
              - General (Folder 24)
              - Katowice region (Folder 25)
            - Letters to ambassadors (Folder 26)
          - Part 2, 1947 January 18-Cases by region. Final report
            - General (Box 156, Folder 1)
            - Polish edition (Folder 2)
            - English edition (Folder 3)
        - Sejm sessions
          - February 4-22 (Folder 4)
          - May 5 (Folder 5)
      - 1952 (Folder 6)
      - 1957
        - General (Folder 7)
        - List of candidates
          - Part 1 (Folder 8)
          - Part 2 (Box 157, Folder 1)
      - 1961
        - General (Folder 2)
        - Correspondence (Folder 3)
        - Reports
          - Protests (Folder 4)
          - Results (Folder 5)
        - Transcripts of Radio Warsaw broadcasts (Folder 6)
      - 1965 (Folder 7)
    - France, Instructions for Polish ambassador in, 1955 July (Folder 8)
    - Genocide of Poles. Report, 1954 (Folder 9)
    - Politics and government
      - Government
        - Chronology of events, 1939-1951 (Folder 10)
        - List of staff and structure in agencies and organizations in 1956 (Folder 11)
      - Internal situation
        - 1945 - Party talks, P.P.S.-P.P.R. Typescript of minutes, July 17 and September 28 (Folder 12)
        - 1945-1946
          - General (Folder 13)
          - Events in the country (Folder 14)
          - Government and party officials (Folder 15)
        - 1946
          - Government and Politburo (Folder 16)
          - Post-referendum conditions (Folder 17)
        - 1946-1947
          - General (Folder 18)
          - Minorities (Folder 19)
          - Polish army (Folder 20)
          - Soviet army (Folder 21)
        - 1947
          - Bierut, Boleslaw, Talks with, February 7 (Folder 22)
          - Deportations of political prisoners to the Soviet Union (Folder 23)
          - Komunisticheskaia Partiia Sovetskego Soiuza - Congress (Folder 24)
          - Soviet military plans and future world conflicts (Folder 25)
          - Stalin, Joseph. Memorandum from Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, 1947 (Folder 26)
          - Underground (Folder 27)
          - Urzad Bezpieczenstwa, Activities of (Folder 28)
          - Wolnosc i Niepodleglosc (top secret) (Folder 29)
        - 1948. Intelligence sources from individuals (Folder 30)
        - 1948-1949. Top secret reports
          - General (Box 158, Folder 1)
          - Contacts in Poland (organized by code symbols)
            - Pi (Folder 2)
            - Vs (Folder 3)
            - Xs (Folder 4)
        - 1960
          - General (Folder 5)
          - Report (Folder 6)
      - Political events
        - 1945-1950 (Folder 7)
        - 1948-1950 (Folder 8)
      - Social democracy, 1918-1939 (Folder 9)
  - Polish Trade Union Centre in Exile (Zwiazki Zawodowe Zagranica), Robotniczy Przeglad Gospodarczy, no. 1 (Folder 10)
  - 1952
  - Political prisoners
    - General
      - General, 1945
        - General (Folder 11)
        - Clippings (Folder 12)
        - Correspondence
          - General (Folder 13)
          - Telegrams (Folder 14)
      - Intelligence sources (Folder 15)
      - Report. "Administration of Justice in Poland of To-Day," n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
    - Banczyk, Piotr, 1951
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Clippings (Folder 18)
    - Boryczka, Adam. Clippings, 1955 (Folder 19)
    - Doboszynski, Adam. Clippings, 1949
      - June (Folder 20)
      - July (Folder 21)
    - Tatar, Stanislaw, 1951
      - General (Folder 22)
      - Calendar (Folder 23)
      - Commentary by British Broadcasting Corporation (Folder 24)
      - Premises
        - General (Box 159, Folder 1)
        - Émigré circles, As interpreted by (Folder 2)
      - Press clippings
        - British (Folder 3)
        - Communist, Polish
          - General (Folder 4)
          - Dziennik Polski (Folder 5)
          - Trybuna Ludu (Folder 6)
          - Wola Ludu (Folder 7)
        - Émigré, Polish-British
          - General (Folder 8)
          - Dziennik Polski i Dziennik Zolnierza (Folder 9)
  - Polowiec, Henryk, Przeciw Zdradzie Socjalizmu i Demokracji, London, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Polska Zjednoczona Partia Robotnicza - Statistics on membership, 1960 (Folder 11)
  - Polskie Centralne Biuro Informacji i Lacznosci, 1948 (Folder 12)
  - Potsdam Conference (Folder 13)
  - Potulicki, Michal, "Some Aspects of the Organization of German Thinking: Facts and Figures: A Report on Intellectual War Criminals," 1944. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Radic, Stjepan-25th anniversary, 1953 (Folder 15)
  - Refugees, Polish
    - General - Communist subversive activities against Poles in foreign countries, 1962 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Canada, Western - Polish organizations and associations, late 50s (Folder 2)
    - Cuba. Biuletyn, 1947-1950 (Folder 3)
    - France
      - Polish Army in France, Origins of, 1940 (Folder 4)
      - Reemigration in 1965 (Folder 5)
      - Resistance
        - General
          - General, 1944-1946 (Folder 6)
          - Printed matter, 1940-1953 (Folder 7)
        - Akcja Monika (Folder 8)
        - Communist agitation, ca. 1940 (Folder 9)
      - Sledziewski, Waclaw, reports for 1940-1943 (Folder 10)
      - Slowo Polskie - Sponsorship question, 1952 (Folder 11)
      - Zwiazek Uczestnikow Polskiego Ruchu Oporu, 1948-1955 (Folder 12)
    - Germany
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - General (Folder 13)
          - Wojtowicz, E. L., letter to Konrad Adenauer 1957 (Folder 14)
        - Personal files of displaced persons
          - B-K (Folder 15)
          - L-M (Folder 16)
          - P-Z (Folder 17)
        - Printed matter, 1948-1951
          - General (Folder 18)
          - Economic, Social and Political Aspects of the Expellee, Munich, 1961 (Folder 19)
          - Polacy w Niemczech, 1948 (Folder 20)
          - Prasa Polskiego Wychodzstwa Przymusowego na Terenie Bylej Rzeszy, 1945 (Folder 21)
      - Adenauer, Konrad, speech, London, 1951 (Folder 22)
      - Brygada Swietokrzyska, "Historia Naczelnych Sil Zbrojnych," 1948-1949 (Folder 23)
      - International Peasant Union, 1950-1952 (Folder 24)
      - Kolo Pogon, "Kurs nowoczesnej mysli wojskowej," 1950 (Folder 25)
      - Komapanie wartownicze, 1947-1948 (Folder 26)
      - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw - Trip to Germany, 1949 (Box 161, Folder 1)
      - Oder-Neisse Area, 1949 (Folder 2)
      - Polish community, Size of, 1947-1948 (Folder 3)
      - Polish-German Youth Association, 1951 (Folder 4)
      - Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe in Germany, 1948-1950 (Folder 5)
      - Syndykat Dziennikarzy Polskich, 1946 (Folder 6)
    - Great Britain
      - General
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Correspondence on Wolnosc i Niepodleglosc and opposition, 1948 or 1949 (anonymous) (Folder 8)
        - Printed matter
          - Free Poland Bulletin, no. 1, 1951 December (Folder 9)
          - Kolo AK: Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1948-1951 (Folder 10)
          - Zycie Polskie na Obczyznie, London, 1950 (Folder 11)
      - Intellectuals and artists
        - A-C (Folder 12)
        - E-L (Folder 13)
        - K-R (Folder 14)
        - S-Z (Folder 15)
      - Ministerstwo Obrony - Meeting organized by General Wladyslaw Bortnowski, 1952 April 27 (Folder 16)
      - Mininisterstwo Sprawiedliwosci - Trial on Wolnosc I Niepodleglosc denunciators, 1954 (Folder 17)
      - Ogolny Zjazd Polakow w Wielkiej Brytanii. Resolutions, London, 1962 October 6-7 (Folder 18)
      - Polski Zwiazek Bylych Wiezniow Politycznych, 1946-1948 (Folder 19)
      - Rada Rzeczpospolitej, 1954-1955 (Folder 20)
      - Skarb Narodowy, 1951-1954 (Folder 21)
      - Swiatowy Zjazd Polski Walczacej, 1966 (Folder 22)
      - Zwiazek Polskich Zolnierzy Zawodowych (Oficerow i Podoficerow) w Wielkiej Brytanii, Bulletin, 1952-1953 (Folder 23)
    - Italy. Informator Inwalidzki, 1952 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - Kenya
      - Printed matter, 1948-1954 (Folder 2)
      - Radio broadcast transcripts (Folder 3)
        - 1946
          - November (Folder 4)
          - December (Folder 5)
        - 1947 January (Folder 6)
    - Palestine. Biuletyn Obozowy, 1947 December (Folder 7)
    - Sweden. "Dzialalnosc i rozwoj emigracji polskiej w Szwecji," 1948. Typescript (Folder 8)
    - United States
      - General, 1941-1955 (Folder 9)
      - American Relief for Poland
        - 1957 (Folder 10)
        - 1962
          - General (Folder 11)
          - United States. Congress (Folder 12)
      - Displaced Persons Act
        - General (Folder 13)
        - Act, 1949-1950 (Folder 14)
        - Application forms (Folder 15)
        - Bill, 1949 January-May (Folder 16)
        - Correspondence (Folder 17)
        - List of applicants in Winzer camp, Germany (Folder 18)
        - Printed matter (Folder 19)
        - Reports (Folder 20)
        - Statements (Folder 21)
      - Federation of Americans of Central and East European Descent - Fraternal organizations, 1946 (Folder 22)
      - National Committee of Americans of Polish Descent
        - Bulletin, 1943, 1948 (Folder 23)
        - Communiqués, 1949-1953 (Folder 24)
        - Documents, 1942-1944 (Folder 25)
      - Polish American Congress
        - General
          - General
            - 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 1)
            - 1955-1956 (Folder 2)
            - 1959-1961 (Folder 3)
            - 1964-1965 (Folder 4)
          - Clippings, 1950-1951 (Folder 5)
          - Correspondence
            - 1947 November-December (Folder 6)
            - 1948
              - January-February (Folder 7)
              - March-April (Folder 8)
          - Declaration of policy, 1945. Bulletin (Folder 9)
          - Memorandum to the United States Senate, 1945 (Folder 10)
          - Rules and regulations, 1946 (Folder 11)
        - Conventions
          - First, 1944. Clippings (Folder 12)
          - Second, 1948
            - Minutes (Folder 13)
            - Press clippings (Folder 14)
            - Report
              - President (Folder 15)
              - United States Congress (Folder 16)
            - Speeches - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw (Folder 17)
          - Third, 1952
            - General (Folder 18)
            - President's report (Folder 19)
          - Fourth, 1956
            - General
              - General (Folder 20)
              - Bulletin (Folder 21)
              - Press clippings (Folder 22)
              - Report
                - General (Folder 23)
                - President (Folder 24)
                - United States. Congress (Folder 25)
              - Resolutions (Box 164, Folder 1)
              - Speeches (Folder 2)
            - By-laws (Folder 3)
            - Commissions (Folder 4)
          - Sixth, 1964
            - General (Folder 5)
            - Press clippings (Folder 6)
            - Reports
              - General (Folder 7)
              - President (Folder 8)
            - Speeches (Folder 9)
        - Komitet Zagraniczny. Report, 1957 (Folder 10)
        - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw, 1949 (Folder 11)
      - Polish Constitution Day, 1959 May (Folder 12)
      - Polish War Relief. Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Folder 13)
      - Syndykat Dziennikarzy Polskich, "Precz z piata kolumna niemiecka," 1942. Typescript (Folder 14)
      - Swiatowy Zwiazek Polakow z Zagranicy. "Pomoc Polonii Amerykanskiej powojennej Polsce," 1942. Typescript (Folder 15)
      - Zjednoczenie Polskie Rzymsko-Katolickie - Speech of Jan Ciechanowski, 1941 (Folder 16)
      - Zwiazek Narodowy Polski - Chairmen and Secretaries in late 50s (Folder 17)
      - Zwiazek Polek w Ameryce-50th Anniversary, 1947 (Folder 18)
  - Retinger, J. H. Clipping, 1944 (Folder 19)
  - Romer, Adam. Obituary, 1965 (Folder 20)
  - Rossi, A., "Soviet Communist Pressure on Western Europe," 1954. Mimeograph (Folder 21)
  - Rowecki, Stefan Grot. Clipping, 1963 (Folder 22)
  - Rozga, Stanislaw. Memoirs, 1947-1948 (Folder 23)
  - Rzepecki, Jan, Po prostu, Warsaw, 1956 (Folder 24)
  - Sadlak, Antoni, 1958 (Folder 25)
  - Sanacja
    - Press, 1953
      - Foreign (Box 165, Folder 1)
      - Polish
        - Communist (Folder 2)
        - Émigré (Folder 3)
    - Skarb Narodowy, 1953-1954 (Folder 4)
    - Walkowicz, Leon T. Appeal to all Poles, 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Sharp, Samuel, Poland: White Eagle on a Red Field. Reviews, 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Sikora, Jan. War memoirs, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw
    - General
      - 1942 (Folder 8)
      - 1943 (Folder 9)
    - Gibraltar catastrophe
      - General
        - General (Folder 10)
        - Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 11)
        - Press
          - 1943
            - General (Folder 12)
            - Polish press in Great Britain (Folder 13)
            - Voice of Poland. Commemorative issue (Folder 14)
          - 1944 (Folder 15)
          - 1962-1963 (Folder 16)
      - Anniversaries
        - First, 1944
          - Press clippings (Folder 17)
          - Speeches (Folder 18)
        - Tenth, 1953
          - General (Folder 19)
          - Correspondence (Folder 20)
        - Twentieth, 1963 (Folder 21)
      - Funeral. Speech of Stanislaw Mikolajczyk (Folder 22)
    - Popiel, Stanislaw, "General Sikorski, jego Polityka i jej Przeciwnicy," 1950 (Folder 23)
  - Slawek, Walery
    - Correspondence - Wasilewski, Leon, 1927 (Folder 24)
    - Essay, "Ideologia obozu marszalka Pilsudzkiego," early 1930s. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - Soroka, W., "Soviet Falsification of Polish History," 1962. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - Soviet Union
    - Espionage. Exposé to the Unites States Senate, 1960 (Folder 27)
    - Germany, East. Agreement of June 1964 (Folder 28)
    - Imperialism, Conference on, Washington, D.C., 1953 (Folder 29)
    - International conflicts with and invasions of. Chronology, 1921-1955 (Folder 30)
    - Poland
      - Consular convention with, 1926 (Folder 31)
      - Influence on Polish affairs. Chart, 1951 (Folder 32)
      - Treaty on double citizenship, 1966 (Folder 33)
    - Political parties, 1942 (Folder 34)
    - Satellites - Communist party leaderships. List, 1962 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - Secret police in World War II. Clipping, 1949 (Folder 2)
    - Vulnerability to political and military attacks, 1950 (Folder 3)
  - Sreniowski, Stanislaw, Dzieje chlopow w Polsce, Warsaw, 1947 (Folder 4)
  - Studentowicz, Kazimierz, "Uspolecznienie wlasnosci prywatnej," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - Szembek, Jan, "Dziennik, 1933-1939." Typescripts (excerpts) (Folder 6)
  - Truman, Harry, Talks with, 1943 April (Folder 7)
  - Tychota, K., Case of, 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Tyrmand, Leopold - Piasecki affair. Clipping, 1956 (Folder 9)
  - United Nations Conference on Freedom of Speech (1948: Geneva) (Folder 10)
  - United Nations Conference on International Organization (1945: San Francisco, Calif.)
    - General (Folder 11)
    - Analysis of Polish experts (Folder 12)
    - Appeals (Folder 13)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Kulerski, Witold (Folder 15)
  - United States
    - Communist threat
      - General, 1959 (Folder 16)
      - Is this Tomorrow: America under Communism, 1947 (comic book) (Folder 17)
    - Congress. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations, Tensions within the Soviet Captive Countries: Poland, 1954 (Folder 18)
  - Wernyhora, Prophecy of, 1795 (Folder 19)
  - World War, 1914-1918 - Przemysl Polish Ukrainian agreement, 1918 November (Folder 20)
  - Wszelaki, Jan, "Free Poles and their Political Life," 1948. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - Yalta Conference (1945)
    - General. Clippings on fifth anniversary, 1950 (Folder 22)
    - Wolfe, Bertram, Poland: Acid Test for a People's Peace. Reprint from Common Sense, 1945 March (Folder 23)